Pavan Raga

www.github.com/pavanraga • www.linkedin.com/in/pavanraga • pavan.raga@u.nus.edu • +65-98612663 463 Pasir Panjang Rd, Singapore 118797

About Me

Highly skilled software engineer with more than 5 years of experience in software development and DevOps. I'm seeking a Software Engineering position involving infrastructure systems or backend. I'm passionate about immutable, reliable, automated infrastructure that scales optimally with organizational needs.

Work Experience

WalletSocket - Cloud Team

Singapore

DevOps Engineer - PT

Aug 2019 - Jan 2020

- Assisted in design and architect of the Pay0k platform which is a payment gateway for merchants to accept various cryptocurrencies like bitcoin, ethereum.
- Responsible for developing and maintaining the CI/CD pipeline for both staging and production environments.
- Utilized Kubernetes extensively to orchestrate the life cycle of polyglot microservices. Followed best practices to develop manifests and integrating the same with continuous delivery.
- Handled increasing traffic load by scaling the backend services/container horizontally by using K8s HPA.

Cisco Systems Inc

Bangalore, India

Software Engineer II

Apr 2018 - Jun 2019

- Independently worked on "Cisco-Capture" tool to enhance the debuggability in live deployments by capturing control and data traffic.
- Moved monolothic application to configure routers to containerized application and deployed them in k8s cluster to provide fault tolerance.

Cisco Systems Inc

Bangalore, India

Software Engineer I

Mar 2016 - May 2018

- Developed Layer 2 features of ASR 903 series of service aggregation routers.
- Implemented "Dying Gasp" support to minimise down time during power outages.
- Built "Autonomous Networking" feature to enable zero touch deployments. This is pull-based infrastructure as Code tool.

AllGo Embedded Systems

Bengalore, India

Software Engineer

Iul 2014 - Feb 2016

- Part of Mirrorlink stack team, a stack which helps in replicating the smartphones display on to car's HMI/infotainment unit.
- Developed CI of software commits using Jenkins to enable fast delivery.
- Built a recovery module for HMI by detecting unhealthy application in the unit and respawning them.

Education

National University of Singapore (NUS)

Singapore

Master of Technology in Software Engineering

Jun 2019 - Jul 2020

- Architecting Cloud Native Scalable Systems, Securing Ubiquitous Systems and Engineering Big Data
- Developed pay0k platform for WalletSocket and deployed into production for south korea region in Jan 2020.

National Institute of Engineering (NIE)

Mysuru, India

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

Jun 2010 - Sep 2014

Professional Certifications

• Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA) Issued by: Linux Foundation

Feb 2020

• AWS Certified Solutions Architect(ACSAA) Issued by: AWS

Apr 2019

Keywords

Languages: Python, C, YAML.

Infrastructure: Kubernetes, Docker, AWS, DigitalOcean **Tools:** Jenkins, Ansible, Jira, Wireshark, VS Code